In this video, we'll look at some imputation methods.
在这个视频里 我们来看几种填充缺失值的方法
And up here, you can see some of the ways that are really common for imputing values.
这里可以看到几种非常常见的填充缺失值方法
And then there are a few really useful resources
这里是几个非常有用的资料链接
linked here in the top part of the notebook.
位于 Notebook 最上面的单元格中
To get started, let's just create our dataset and read in the necessary libraries.
首先创建数据集 然后导入需要的库
For imputation, in this particular example,
在这个示例中
we will be working with pandas and not scikit-learn,
我们使用 Pandas 来填充缺失值 而不是 scikit-learn
but scikit-learn pre-processing library is really
但是 scikit-learn 的 pre-processing 库真的很有用
useful and is commonly done with machine learning algorithms.
经常和其他机器学习算法一起使用
Pandas, I find really intuitive and pretty easy to use,
Pandas 也是非常直观、易用的库
so that'll be what we work with through this example.
所以我们会在这个示例中使用 Pandas
However, you could use
不过 你也可以选择
the pre-processing library if you're more comfortable with that as well.
使用 pre-processing 库 如果你对其更加熟悉
Okay. So the first question said,
第一个问题是
"Use the dictionary below to label the columns with the appropriate data type."
用下面的字典 标注出每列对应的数据类型
So just looking at this,
看一下数据
it looks like column A is numeric or quantitative in nature,
列 A 看上去是数值型的
column B is also quantitative,
列 B 也是数值型的
but A, it looks like a float if that mattered,
但是 A 更像是浮点数
B is an integer,
而 B 则是整数
C is all NaNs,
C 全是缺失值
so that could go any way.
也就是说 它可以是任意类型
D, it looks like Boolean,
D 看上去是 布尔值
and then E looks like it's also categorical in nature.
E 看上去像是分类变量
It has yes, no, and maybe.
其中有 Yes、No 和 Maybe 这些类别
So let's go ahead and just fill those in.
现在对下面的字典进行填充
So A is quantitative.
A 是数值型的
B is also quantitative.
B 也是数值型的
C, we can't tell because it's all NaNs.
C 不知道是哪种类型 因为全都是 NaN
D is Boolean so we could treat that it's either quantitative.
D 是布尔型的 但我们也可以将其处理为其他类型
It could just be like one,
可以将其看作 1/0 这样的数值类型
zero for quantitative or it could be like true/false or like yes/no.
True/False 也可以是 yes/no 这样的形式
So it could go either way,
可以转换为任意一种形式
but it's a Boolean.
但确实也是布尔值
And then E is categorical.
E 是一个分类变量
So it's okay. And looks like that went through okay.
好了 通过了
And then our other columns or rows that you feel comfortable dropping,
数据中有没有可以放心删除的行或列?
so in general, I think we should feel comfortable dropping this column.
总的来说 我们完全可以放心地删除 C 列
All the rows, there aren't any rows with all missing values,
但行里面 没有哪行是全都缺失的
and so we probably don't want to drop any of those,
所以 我们可能并不想删除哪一行
but we could definitely drop this column C. And then,
但一定可以删除这里的 C 列
if we actually drop that,
我们实际删除一下
we're creating this new data frame,
创建了一个新的 DataFrame new_df
we're dropping column C,
用 drop 函数删除 C 列
and axis equals one specifies that it's the column and not the row.
让 axis 等于 1 指定删除的是列而不是行
Cool. So using new_df,
接下来使用 new_df
I wrote a lambda function that you can use to impute
我编写了一个 lambda 函数 用均值填充缺失值
the mean for the columns in the data frame using the apply method.
可以通过 apply 方法应用到 new_df 的各列
So here, basically, we have this col.mean,
这里基本上就是用 col.mean()
fillna, and we're doing it across the rows,
fillna 函数 沿着行的方向依次应用
So check what you need to answer the question below.
没有运行成功 将下面的选项填到相应的位置
So why did this break?
为什么报错了呢?
So we're taking the column,
我们获取每列
we're taking the mean of the column and then we're filling it, and we're saying,
取其均值 之后用均值对列中的缺失值进行填充
"Do that for each of the columns."
对数据中的每一列都应用这个函数
So it fills the mean,
选项 a "用均值填充 但是在这种情况下没有现实意义"
It gives an error. Okay. And we should look at this on a column by column basis.
选项 b "返回了一个错误" 好的 我们来看一下每一列的情况
Okay. So let's say we're trying to fill the mean.
假设我们要用均值来填充这些缺失值
So if we try to fill the mean of this, that should be fine.
如果用均值填充这一列 不会有什么问题
We'll take the mean of two, zero, seven,
因为会取这里的 2、0、7、10、15 的均值
10, and 15, and we should put those two values here.
然后把均值填充在这两个 NaN 的位置上
Column B doesn't actually have any missing value so we don't have to worry about that.
B 列其实并没有任何缺失值 所以不用考虑
Column C, I don't know what that's going to
C 列 其实根本不知道能填充什么
do when we try to fill the mean because we don't have any numbers to work with.
因为其中根本就没有任何数值可以计算
Column D, so if we treat these as numbers,
D 列 如果把这些值当作数字的话
we should get back like a 0.5 in there.
应该能返回均值 0.5
But then, what does that mean in terms of true and false?
但是 对于 True/False 来说 0.5 意味着什么?
That didn't really make a lot of sense.
这样并没有现实意义
So column D doesn't really make sense.
所以 D 用均值填充没什么意义
Column C, I'm not really sure.
C 不是很确定
Column A should be fine,
A 应该是没问题的
and column E again,
然后是 E
taking the mean, I don't really know how that would work because there is a yes,
我不知道这里的均值如何计算 因为只有 Yes、No 和 Maybe
no, and a maybe, so I don't know how to impute the mean.
不确定这里如何用均值填充
The only one that really makes sense to impute the mean on is column A.
用均值填充缺失值 唯一有意义的是 A 列
And Column C, we actually dropped,
C 列 我们其实已经删除了
so we don't have to worry about that.
所以不需要去考虑
So column A, it makes sense.
A 是可以的
So there should be no problem.
应该是选项 c "没有问题 该列可以按预期用均值填充"
Column E was the yes, no, maybe,
E 是 Yes、No 和 Maybe 所在列
and that one probably gives the error
这一列很可能会报错
because we don't really know what's happening with that.
因为不知道这个均值到底该如何计算
And then with the true/false,
然后是 True/False 所在列
it's going to fail what the mean but that's going to be a 0.5.
虽然也可以用均值填充 也就是 0.5
So what does that mean in terms of true and false?
但是 0.5 对于 True/False 来说是什么意思?
It doesn't really make a lot of sense.
其实并没有现实意义
And so then, there's a little comment but
这里 还可以看到一些额外的评论
that can sort of make sure that you understand why that's true.
确保你真的理解了这个练习的答案
So only the first one does the mean make any sense.
只有第一列是可以用均值来填充缺失值的
The true/false gives you back a 0.5 which
True/False 的列的均值是 0.5
doesn't really make sense in the realm of true and false.
但是这个值对于 True/False 来说没有意义
And then column B just breaks
B 列直接会报错 (此处口误 应该是 E 列)
because we can't take the mean of a bunch of categorical things.
因为不能对分类变量求均值
Okay. So given the results above,
看了上面的结果
it might make more sense to follow what mode it says.
某些列用众数来填充可能更有意义
So here, just write a function that imputes the mode,
自己编写一个函数 用众数填充缺失值
and then there's some documentation here we can use.
这里还有一处参考资料链接
Looks like we can get them out like this.
好像可以这样来获取众数
So for each column,
对每一列
we want to take the mode in this way.
我们可以通过这种方式获取众数
And if we go back here,
回到练习中
I'll just call this thing fill_mode,
将这个函数叫做 fill_mode
and then it's just going to be a lambda expression similar to what we had up here.
其实是跟之前的 lambda 表达式非常相似的
So I'm just going to take the same idea.
直接复制过来
Okay. So if we do a fill mode,
如果要用众数填充的话
we should be able to do something where we use this.
主要就是用到刚才看到的代码
It's like they do called up fillna,
调用 fillna 函数
and then I'm just going to say call mode,
然后调用 mode 函数
and it looks like they did something a little different.
不过好像与 mean 有点不同
So they took the column mode and then they did an index of zero.
他们先对列调用 mode() 然后再取索引 0 的值
So you might have to do something like that. Show you what it's like.
所以 我们也要这样做
And then I'm just going to say fill_mode.
将下面改为 fill_mode
Okay. So now, actually,
好了 现在来看一下
let's take a look at our dataset. So new_df.
我们的数据集 new_df1
All right.
好的
So when we look at this,
我们来看一下
when we're looking at the mode of A,
A 这一列的众数
there actually wasn't one,
因为该列其实并不存在众数
so imputed zero into these values.
所以程序就把 0 作为众数进行了填充
But zero's not actually the mode.
但是 0 其实并不是真正的众数
It's just one of the numbers.
它只是其中的一个值
I want to say, does not impute them.
所以 我会在这边填 a
There isn't a mode so it just like chooses one of the numbers.
这一列没有众数 所以好像就只是选了其中一个数字
I'm not really sure how it did that.
我也不是特别清楚是如何选择的
We could look in the docs and see how that happened.
回头可以查一下 mode 的文档
And then filling column D,
关于 D 列
it's kind of interesting again.
这里也比较有趣
This didn't fill the mode either because there was
这一列也没有填充均值
an even number of trues and falses before.
因为这一列的 True 和 False 的数量是相同的
So if we look up here,
看一下上面的数据
there's two falses and two trues.
这一列有两个 False 两个 True
So we have two true values,
两个 True 两个 False
two false values, and then it just shows false and filled-in false.
结果用 False 填充了缺失值
So there wasn't a mode in this.
也就是说 这一列也没有众数
It just sort of filled in false and it just filled in false for all of these values,
好像就是选出了 False 来填充这些缺失值
which maybe, there's something in the documentation to say,
有可能文档里面这样规定
"Choose the lowest number."
如果所有值的的频数相同 选择最小的数字
and fill that if they're all equal or this is considered a zero value, too.
因为 False 也会被当作 0
Maybe it just fills zero.
所以这里也相当于填充的是 0
But in either case,
但不管是什么情况
these two didn't really fill the mode and then,
这两列并没有真正用众数填充
yes, if we go back and look at this again.
对于最后一列 回到之前的数据
So yes shows up here and then no, maybe, and then yes.
可以看到 Yes 出现的要比 No 和 Maybe 多
So there's two yeses and then only one no one one maybe.
有两个 Yes、一个 No、一个 Maybe
So at least here, if there's a yes,
至少在这一列 如果填充的值是 Yes
yes, yes, it filled the mode.
就说明确实用众数来填充的
That is it filled the thing that happened the most.
也就是说 用出现次数最多的值进行了填充
So the mode for a categorical variable is just the one that occurred the most.
对于分类变量 的确有填充众数
This is true.
这是对的
So again, here, we should be really careful
再次强调 用均值填充
when imputing the mean because there are some cases that just don't work,
缺失值的时候 我们要非常小心 因为有一些情况会报错
and when imputing the mode,
用众数填充时
there are some cases that "work" but they don't really make sense or they might not
有一些情况虽然看似可行 但是并没有实际意义
be exactly the best for our situation
即使确实可以填充 获得一种结果
even if it actually fills in and we can get results from it.
但很可能也并不是最佳解决方案